<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<questionPath name="cli-input-identification-dialogue-review">
    <question
        id="repository_cli_scan"
        llm_alias="gpt-4o-mini"
        mode="direct"
        role="repository_cli_scanner"
        timeout="240"
        request_timeout="30"
        retry_delay="5">
        <description>
            Identify likely command-line entry points and input requirements from repository evidence.
        </description>
        <prompt>
Original user request:
{prompt}

You are analyzing a software repository in order to identify how it can be executed from the command line.

Task:
Produce an initial technical assessment of the repository CLI interface.

Focus on:
1. likely executable files;
2. files containing if __name__ == "__main__";
3. scripts declared in pyproject.toml, setup.py, setup.cfg, Makefile, shell scripts, or README files;
4. argparse, click, typer, fire, hydra, configargparse, absl, docopt, or custom sys.argv parsing;
5. required positional arguments;
6. optional arguments;
7. expected input file types;
8. expected input directories;
9. default values;
10. examples of possible commands.

Return a structured report with these sections:
- Candidate entry points
- CLI parsing mechanisms
- Required inputs
- Optional inputs
- File and directory inputs
- Environment variables
- Evidence still missing
- Initial executable command hypotheses

Use only evidence provided in the original request. If the request does not contain repository evidence, state what information is needed.
        </prompt>
    </question>

    <question
        id="input_semantics_inference"
        llm_alias="gemini-2.5-flash"
        mode="direct"
        role="input_semantics_inference"
        timeout="240"
        request_timeout="30"
        retry_delay="5">
        <description>
            Infer the semantic meaning of CLI inputs and propose minimal valid test inputs.
        </description>
        <prompt>
Original user request:
{prompt}

Initial CLI scan:
{repository_cli_scan.answer}

You are the second analyst in a dialogue among LLMs.

Task:
Infer the semantic meaning of the CLI inputs identified by the first analyst.

For each candidate entry point:
1. explain what the program appears to do;
2. explain what each required input probably represents;
3. identify whether each input is a path, file, directory, integer, float, string, enum, flag, URL, model name, dataset name, or configuration object;
4. infer minimal valid input values for a smoke test;
5. infer likely file extensions and minimal file contents when possible;
6. identify inputs that cannot be safely guessed;
7. identify inputs that require repository-specific data.

Return:
- Refined input schema per entry point
- Minimal smoke-test command per entry point
- Synthetic input files that may be needed
- Inputs that must not be guessed
- Open questions for the next reviewer

Do not invent repository facts. Separate evidence-based conclusions from hypotheses.
        </prompt>
    </question>

    <question
        id="execution_risk_review"
        llm_alias="claude-haiku-4-5"
        mode="direct"
        role="execution_risk_reviewer"
        timeout="240"
        request_timeout="30"
        retry_delay="5">
        <description>
            Review the inferred CLI inputs for execution risks, unsupported assumptions, and reproducibility problems.
        </description>
        <prompt>
Original user request:
{prompt}

Initial CLI scan:
{repository_cli_scan.answer}

Input semantics inference:
{input_semantics_inference.answer}

You are the third analyst in a dialogue among LLMs.

Task:
Critically review the proposed CLI input identification.

Check:
1. whether candidate entry points are justified by evidence;
2. whether required inputs are complete;
3. whether any inferred input values are unsafe or unsupported;
4. whether any generated synthetic files could cause misleading execution results;
5. whether the proposed smoke tests are likely to terminate;
6. whether the commands risk starting training, downloading large datasets, using GPUs, writing many files, or calling external services;
7. whether additional static analysis is required before execution.

Return:
- Accepted assumptions
- Rejected assumptions
- High-risk commands
- Safer alternative commands
- Missing repository evidence
- Recommended constraints for execution
- Revised smoke-test plan

Prefer conservative execution. The goal is to identify CLI inputs, not to run expensive experiments.
        </prompt>
    </question>

    <question
        id="final_cli_input_plan"
        llm_alias="gpt-5-mini"
        mode="direct"
        role="final_cli_input_identification_plan"
        timeout="300"
        request_timeout="30"
        retry_delay="5">
        <description>
            Produce the final project-review answer: a precise CLI input identification plan for repository execution.
        </description>
        <prompt>
Original user request:
{prompt}

CLI scan:
{repository_cli_scan.answer}

Input semantics inference:
{input_semantics_inference.answer}

Execution risk review:
{execution_risk_review.answer}

You are the final analyst.

Task:
Produce the final answer for a project review.

The answer must explain how the multi-LLM dialogue identifies CLI inputs for a repository.

Include:
1. the objective of the dialogue;
2. the role of each LLM step;
3. the expected input to the dialogue;
4. the expected output of the dialogue;
5. the final CLI input schema format;
6. the final command-generation format;
7. how uncertainty is represented;
8. how unsafe or expensive commands are avoided;
9. how the result can be used by an automated repository execution system;
10. a compact example of the final output schema.

The final output schema must include:
- entry_point
- invocation_type
- confidence
- evidence
- required_arguments
- optional_arguments
- required_files
- required_directories
- environment_variables
- generated_test_files
- smoke_test_command
- forbidden_or_risky_commands
- unresolved_questions

Return the answer in English.
Use a scientific and technical style.
Avoid marketing language.
        </prompt>
    </question>

</questionPath>